《小鬼当家4：玩转新居》
薇薇，我知道只剩三天购物日了 但客户打电话来说…
Viv, I know there are only three shopping days left, but they called,
他们想在一小时后 去你看的房子
and they want to see your house in an hour.
啊哈
Uh-huh.
妈！叫巴兹关掉音乐
Mom! Make Buzz turn off the music.
- 没问题 - 妈！
- No problem. - Mom!
- 妈 - 等一下，薇薇
- "Mom." - Hang on, Viv.
- 让你姐姐好好排练 - 希望这会有所帮助
- Let your sister rehearse. - Like that'll help.
- 去把厨房打扫一下 - 但是…
- And clean up the kitchen. - But…
好了，薇薇，稍后见
Now. Okay, Viv. I'll see you in a bit.
我说过要你去打扫一下厨房
I thought I told you to clean up the kitchen.
- 我已经搞定了，今晚我可以和朋友去看电影吗？ - 不行
I did. Can I go to the movies tonight with some friends?
- 不 - 不…
- No. - No…
不，不行，我要带客户去看房子，你得照顾凯文
No, no. I'm showing a house, and I need you to baby-sit Kevin.
为何不叫梅根呢？
Well, why can't Megan do it?
她要排练啊
Because she has to go to rehearsal at the teen center.
你不一定要去看电影啊
And you don't have to go to the movies.
我不去，生活就乐趣了
I do if I want a life.
你得照顾凯文 他人在哪里？凯文！
You're baby-sitting Kevin. Hey, where is he, anyway? Kevin.
- 这是什么？这是什么？ - 是车子！
- What is it? What is it? - It's a car!
- 喔！ - 等等，那是…
- Whoa! - Wait a second. That was…
亲爱的，那是我的
Honey, that was mine.
太棒了 又有天线，什么都有
That was awesome. It's got an antenna and everything.
- 圣诞快乐，妈妈 - 圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas, Mommy. - Merry Christmas.
- 圣诞快乐 - 在那
- Merry Christmas. - Over here.
- 送我什么礼物？ - 这是什么？
- What did I get? - What is this?
- 谢谢 - 大家一起来录像
- Thank you. - Okay, everybody get in the shot.
- 大家一起来 - 好的
- Everybody get together. - Okay.
- 好，圣诞快乐 - 圣诞快乐
All right. Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas.
- 圣诞快乐 - 非常欢乐，巴兹
Merry Christmas. Very funny, Buzz.
- 去年的圣诞节影片吗？ - 对啊
- Last Christmas, huh? - Yeah.
今年的圣诞节将不再有欢乐
This Christmas isn't gonna be any fun.
当然会有欢乐
Well, of course it will.
亲爱的，我们会像从前 做一样的事
Honey, we're gonna do all the same things we've always done.
与家人和朋友…一起唱圣诞歌
Sing Christmas carols, be with family and friends,
把饼干和牛奶放在外面 等待圣诞老人的来临
put cookies and milk out for Santa.
- 一切如同往常 - 除了今年…
- It's gonna be just the same. - Except this year…
没有了爸爸
no Dad.
没错，就只有这点不一样
Right. That's the one thing that's different.
你们两人为什么不复合呢？
Why can't you just get back together?
亲爱的，我们这样做 也是迫不得已啊
Honey, we're just gonna have to let that go.
也就是说不可能，对吗？
That's a no, right?
毕竟无法事事如意
It means some things are just out of our control.
我知道你想念你爸爸
I know you miss your dad.
他非常爱我
And he loves me very much.
你们两人都很爱我 但是却没有办法复合
You both do, and it has nothing to do with me.
- 他告诉了你吗？ - 我已经九岁了，我看了很多电视
- Did he tell you that? - I'm nine years old. I watch a lot of TV.
他因为我而离开的吗？
Did he leave because of me?
不是，当然不是
No. Of course not.
我就知道，一定是因为巴兹和梅根
I knew it! It was Buzz and Megan.
喔，不是因为任何人或任何事情
Oh, it wasn't anyone… or any one thing.
不然是因为什么？
Then what was it?
这一切都一言难尽啊
That's not easy to explain.
但，嗯，有时候当…
But, uh, sometimes when…
人们结婚很久以后 他们会感到枯燥乏味
people are married for a long time, they get into kind of a rut.
- 你知道什么是枯燥乏味？ - 知道，比如说，当人们不再感到欢乐…
- You know what a rut is? - Yeah. When people aren't having any fun,
并且真的觉得厌烦时
and they're really bored.
就是那样
Kind of like that.
你要下楼吗？
Now, will you come downstairs?
快点准备
When you're ready.
嘿！
Hey!
等一下
Wait a second.
- 凯文，进来 - 快点，你必须看看这个！
- Kevin, come in here. - Yeah, hurry, you've gotta see this!
喔！嘿！嘿！
Ow! Hey! Hey!
- 你总是喜欢那样 - 让我起来，豆花脸！
- You always fall for that. - Let me up, zit-face!
- 笨蛋，你什么时候才学的会啊 - 放开你弟弟
- Lamebrain. When are you gonna learn? - Get off your brother.
你不用排练了吗？
And shouldn't you be rehearsing?
你要怎么去青少年中心？
How are you getting to the teen center?
娅希莉的妈妈会来接我
Ashley's mom's picking me up in a half hour.
能让我去看电影吗？
Can I please go to the movies?
不行，我说过你要照顾凯文
No. I told you. You're watching Kevin.
- 让他去吧，我可以一个人待在家 - 不行
- Please let him go. I'll stay home alone. - No.
- 我曾经做过啊 - 别令我想起往事
- I've done it before. - Don't remind me.
你浪费了我整个夜晚
You loused up my whole night.
要是我不好过 你也别想好到哪里去
And if I'm gonna be miserable, you're gonna be miserable.
妈妈！
Mom!
- 哈啰，是我 - 爸爸！
- Hello. It's me. - Dad!
- 爸爸！ - 嘿，乖儿子
- Dad! - Hey, big guy!
我不知道你今晚会来
I didn't know you were coming tonight.
- 喔，我想给你一个惊喜 - 嘿，爸爸
- Oh, I thought I'd surprise you. - Hey, Dad.
嘿，巴兹
Hey, Buzz.
喔，凯特，我的天 很不错的房子
Oh, Kate. Gosh, the place looks great.
真的装饰得很好
Really nice decorations.
- 跟往年一样 - 因此，嗯…
- Same as every year. - So, um,
爸爸，你今晚怎么会来？
Dad, why'd you come tonight?
其实，我想和你妈妈谈谈
Actually, I want to talk to your mom about something.
私下谈谈
Privately.
- 你想过爸爸会回家吗？ - 啊，凯文
- Do you think he wants to come home? - Aw, Kev.
- 聊什么？ - 没有，就是单纯问候
- What? - No "Hello, how are ya?"
对不起，我有个生意要忙 彼得，你到底想干什么？
I'm sorry. I have a business appointment, Peter. What do you want?
好吧，我本来不想要再次面对婚姻 但…
Okay, gosh. I wasn't gonna jump right into it, but…
你知道娜塔莉的 我们已经住在一起，嗯…
Well, you know Natalie and I are living together, and, uh,
因此当我们离婚后 我就要和她结婚
well, when our divorce is final, I'm gonna marry her.
真的？
Really?
你要再婚
You're getting married again.
喔，那，嗯…那…
Wow. That's, uh… that…
我们只分居了八个月
Wow. We've only been separated eight months.
我…事情发生得如此突然
Yeah, I… it just happened real quickly, and…
听着，凯特…
Listen, Kate,
我真的想要和孩子们 一起度过这一段假期
I really want the kids to spend a little time with me over the holidays.
你想要和孩子们一起过圣诞节？
You want the kids for Christmas?
只要两天，我想要他们更加认识娜塔莉
Just a couple of days. I want them to get to know Natalie better.
喔，因为她就要成为他们的继母了
Oh, because she's gonna be their, uh, stepmother.
是
Yeah.
你得去问他们
Well, you're gonna have to ask them.
我知道
I know.
我该怎么找朋友？
How am I supposed to see my friends?
那只有几天时间
It's only for a few days.
但对我来说 这么长的时间会让友情变淡
Well, duh, but that's just long enough for me to fall out of the loop.
的确，但你不能要求我们
Yeah, you can't expect us.
- 放弃假期 - 怎么样，凯文？
- to give up our vacation. - Well, Kevin?
将会有一个皇室家庭来拜访
There's a royal family coming to visit.
他们有一位你同年龄的男孩
They have a son around your age.
你有机会和王子一起玩
Actually, you might have a chance to play with a crown prince.
- 王子？ - 是不是很酷啊？
- A crown prince? - Wouldn't that be cool?
- 的确很酷 - 你肯定不会相信那个房间…
- Yeah, way cool. - Yeah, and you guys wouldn't believe.
娜塔莉为你布置的那个房间
the room that Natalie has set up for you.
你的答案呢？
Well, what do you say?
我想我还是不要
I think I'm gonna pass.
因为在圣诞节离开家，这是不对的
It just wouldn't be right leaving the family at Christmas.
- 我确信你会理解 - 是的，我能理解
- I'm sure you understand. - Yeah. Yeah, I do.
这…这算是一个公开的邀约吗？
Well, it's… it's… it's an open invitation, hmm?
我不会太晚回家
And I won't be back too late.
既然你都要待在家 多少做一些家务事吧
And since you're staying home, it wouldn't hurt to do some of your chores.
是，夫人
Yes, ma'am.
我会做好家务事的
I'll make sure they get done.
来打扫吧，干酪脸
Clean it, cheese-face.
喔！
Ow!
哇！
Oops.
我不小心的！
My fault.
哈啰，我回家了
Hello, I'm home…
嘿
Hey.
- 怎么样？ - 很糟糕
- How'd it go? - Awful.
我讨厌巴兹，我永远都不想 和他单独待在家里
I hate Buzz, and I never want to be stuck home alone with him as long as I live.
喔，宝贝 我知道他找你麻烦
Oh, honey. I know he picks on you.
找麻烦？ 他是羞辱我，折磨我
Picks on me? Humiliates me, tortures me.
我不想变成这里所有人的出气筒
I'm sick of being everyone's favorite joke around here.
是，是 当最小的孩子是很难受的
Yeah. Yeah, it's hard to be the youngest.
我讨厌巴兹 但愿我没有哥哥和姐姐
Well, I hate Buzz. I wish I didn't have a brother or a sister.
- 你不是这个意思 - 是，就是这个意思！
- Well, you don't mean that. - Yes, I do!
我希望就只有我一个小孩！
I wish I was an only child!
好了 我很抱歉让你这么不高兴
Well… I'm sorry that you're so unhappy.
也许你应该到你房间想想 珍惜你所拥有的
Maybe you should go to your room and think about what you have,
而不是你没有的东西
rather than what you don't have.
只有孩子们不知道 他们拥有是多么的美好
Only children don't know how good they have it.
要是巴兹和梅根不在 生活会多么美好啊
Life would be perfect if Buzz and Megan weren't around.
我想要一个真正喜欢我的家庭 这样会太过分吗？
I mean, is it too much to ask for a family who actually likes me?
我得逃跑
I'd run away…
如果我知道能逃到哪里的话
if I knew where to run to.
嘿，对了！
Hey, I do!
我有一个公开的邀请
I have an open invitation.
我解不开我的安全带
Can't get my seat belt unfastened.
谢谢，亚伦
Thanks, Alan.
谢谢
Thanks.
喔，多么不可思议的夜晚
Oh, what an incredible evening.
以及一个不错的夜间工作
And not a bad night's work.
我们为了那些孩子 慈善募款了两百万
We raised over two million for those children's charities.
开门
Door, open.
我就要和芝加哥两位最大的客户签约了
And I am on the verge of signing two of the biggest clients in Chicago.
因为你是世界上最厉害的公关
That's because you're the best publicist in the world.
关门
Doors, close.
我需要感谢你的大力宣传吗？
Have I remembered to thank you for telling everyone that?
打开炉火 今晚，你要不要来…
Fire, light. Not tonight you haven't.
我应该对你表示感激
Perhaps I ought to show my appreciation.
放音乐
Music, on.
关上窗帘
Curtains, close.
啊，事情正在逐渐好转中…
Aw, nuts. Just when things were getting good.
漂亮的房子，嗯，宝贝？
Nice house, huh, pumpkin?
没错，马文！你想不想进去抢劫啊？
Sure is, Marv. You sure you don't wanna rob it?
不，不，我并不想要
No. No, I don't wanna rob it.
我的抢劫生涯已经结束了
My robbery days are over.
亲爱的！我们将会得到很多钱，好吗？
Look, darling, we're moving up to the big money. All right?
而且是来得容易的钱，不需要中间人
The easy money. No middleman.
赚的都纯利润，只要谨慎小心的执行
Pure profit. Strictly a class operation, huh?
就几个词：「薇拉」、「绑架」
Three words, Vera. Kid-na-pping.
我认为那是一个词
I think that's only one word.
我们只需要待到皇室的到来…
We're gonna wait for the royals to arrive…
然后我们就绑架那个王子
hup, dup, dodey-do and then we're gonna kidnap the prince.
「喔，别绑架我」
"Oh, don't kidnap me. I'm fancy."
你觉得我们会成功吗？
You sure we can pull it off?
不需要哈利帮忙计划吗？
I mean, without Harry making the plans?
哈利的计划会帮我们什么？ 只会帮我们进监牢
Look where Harry's plans kept landing me, huh? In jail.
- 嗯 - 好了，这次不要
- Mmm. - Well, not this time.
因为这次…
Because this time…
我是老大
I'm the boss.
谁是老大？
Yeah. Who's the boss?
- 你是老大 - 我喜欢结婚，嗯？
- You're the boss. - I love being married. Eh?
- 我的乖女孩 - 嘿！
- That's my girl. - Hey!
- 太好了 - 喔！他们好像有访客到来
- All right. - Oh! Looks like they got a visitor.
就是这个地方吗？
This where you want to go?
是的，就是这里
Yeah, this is the place.
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
零钱留给你吧
Keep the change.
这全部都是零钱
It's all change.
你是谁？
Who are you?
对不起，夫人
Beg your pardon, ma'am.
是的，普雷斯特？
Yes, Prescott?
有一个小孩子说要拜访麦卡斯特先生 他说是他的儿子
Mr. McCallister has a visitor. The young man claims to be his son.
好吧，带他进来
Well, send him in.
- 凯文！ - 爸爸！
- Kevin! - Dad!
嘿！喔！我以为你不来了
Hey! Oh! I thought you said weren't coming.
我想到
Well, I started thinking,
如果小孩都只和妈妈 一起过圣诞节，那是很不公平的
"Hey, it's not fair if Mom gets all the kids for Christmas."
圣诞节怎么能不和小孩一起过呢，对吧？
What's Christmas without kids, right?
对，哈啰，凯文
Right. Hello, Kevin.
嗨，娜塔莉 希望你不介意我临时的来访…
Hi, Natalie. I hope you don't mind me just dropping in like this,
但我爸爸真的邀请了我
but my dad did invite me.
- 是，我知道 - 那邀请是公开的吗？
- Yes, I know. - So is the invitation still open?
当然是 茉莉，请你过来一下
Of course it is. Molly, would you come here, please?
我一直期待着和你一起过圣诞节
I've been looking forward to spending time with you.
你爸爸和我聊过很多关于你的事迹
Your dad talks about you kids a lot.
巴兹是个捣乱鬼，但我是人见人爱的
Buzz is the troublemaker. I'm the adorable one.
喔，茉莉
Oh. Ah, Molly.
这位是凯文·麦卡斯特 他要和我们一起待上几天
This is Kevin McCallister, and he's going to be staying with us for a few days.
你可以为他 准备一个客房吗？
Would you make up the special guest room?
啊，客房
Ah, the special guest room.
马上准备，夫人
Right away, ma'am.
- 还有！普雷斯特，给凯文一把房子的遥控器 - 好的，夫人
- Oh, and Prescott, give Kevin a house key. - If you say so, ma' am.
这是什么遥控器？
What kind of key is this?
这是整栋房子的遥控器
It's a key to the whole house.
这是一栋智能型住宅，凯文 它会执行你所吩咐的事
This is a smart house, Kevin. It does whatever you tell it to.
熄灭炉火
Fire, out.
打开窗帘
Curtains, open.
喔！我想我会喜欢这里的
Wow! I think I'm gonna like it here.
来吧，试试看
Go ahead. You try.
开门
Door, open.
喔！这里真的很酷
Wow! This stuff is so cool.
喔，我的天！喔，我的天！
Oh, my gosh! Oh, my gosh!
这么酷的东西！
This is such cool stuff! Ah!
喔！看看这游戏！
Oh! Look at this game!
这是电玩专用椅！喔！
This chair's a remote control chair! Oh!
喔，太棒了！
Oh, yeah!
这太酷了！喔！
This is so cool! Oh!
- 你觉得这里舒服吗？ - 太舒服了！
- Think you'll be comfortable here? - I'll say!
谢谢，娜塔莉 这是有史以来最好的圣诞节！
Thanks, Natalie. This is gonna be the best Christmas ever!
该熄灯了，凯文
Lights out, Kev.
嘿，凯文？
Hey, Kevin?
凯文！
Kevin.
这个孩子又躲去哪里了？
How many times can I lose this child?
凯文
Kevin.
- 喂 - 凯特，我…
- Hello. - Kate, I…
…想告诉你，凯文在我这边
I want to let you know Kevin just got here.
喔，谢天谢地…
Oh, thank God.
他安全的在你那边…
He got there… safely.
- 我正想要打电话给你，但是… - 你没事吧？
- I was gonna call you, but, uh… - You okay?
没事，我人很好
Yeah. Yes, I'm fine.
谢谢你让他过来
Well… thanks for letting him come.
- 谢谢你的电话 - 圣诞快乐
- Well, thanks for calling. - Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
早安，凯文
Good mornin', Kevin.
早安
Good morning.
- 是谁？ - 过来，亲爱的
- Who's there? - Over here, dear.
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
来吃早餐了，任何餐点都随便你叫
Breakfast time. Anything special you'd like?
任何餐点都可以？
Anything?
任何餐点
Anything.
- 喔！ - 有时候我等不及圣诞老人的到来…
- Wow! - Sometimes I can't wait for Santa to come,
所以我要去帮自己买礼物
so I end up doing some shopping by myself.
- 你想要开个礼物吗？ - 不，你宠坏他了
- Would you like to open one? - No, you're gonna spoil him.
- 爸爸，这是她的房子 - 如果她想宠坏我的话，她当然可以
Dad, it's her house. If she wants to spoil me, she can spoil me.
好吧，但只能一个
All right. All right, but just one.
但不要开最大的…
And not… the biggest one.
这真的会飞吗？
Does it really fly?
真的会，但只能在外面飞
It really does, but only outside.
- 我们不喜欢搞坏任何东西 - 喔，谢谢你，娜塔莉！
- We don't want to break anything. - Wow! Thanks, Natalie!
你们为什么要离开？ 圣诞节就快要到了
Why do you have to leave? It's so close to Christmas.
我知道，但是帮娜塔莉募款的皇室就要来了…
Yeah, I know, but the royal family's coming for one of Natalie's fund-raisers,
我的工作就是确保这件事 能完美精彩的上新闻报导
and it's my job to make sure the event's well-covered by press and photographers.
嘿，这不会很久的
Hey, it's not gonna take that long,
我不会占用你其余的假期时间
and I won't have to work for the rest of your vacation, okay?
如果你有任何需求的话 就叫普雷斯特，他会帮忙你的
And if you need anything, ask Prescott. He'll take care of you.
很酷的飞机吧？
It's a cool plane, huh?
我猜她是想要讨好我
I think she's trying to buy my affection.
- 凯文 - 怎么了？
- Kevin. - What?
我没说这样子不好
I'm not saying it's a bad thing.
我很开心有你在这里
I'm glad you're here.
普雷斯特先生 可以帮我一个忙吗？
Mr. Prescott, can I ask you a question?
可以
Yes.
可以帮我做一杯奶昔吗？
Can you make a milk shake?
有巧克力吗？
Do you have chocolate?
娜塔莉说我想要什么就有什么
What? Natalie said anything I need.
- 你现在就需要一杯奶昔，是吗？ - 要巧克力口味的
- And you need a milk shake, do you? - A chocolate one.
你觉得今年圣诞节会下雪吗？
Do you think we'll have a white Christmas?
这似乎不太可能，因为最近的气温相当异常
Seems highly unlikely, given the recent unseasonable temperatures.
这是什么？一个小电梯吗？
What's this thing? A mini elevator?
这是食物升降机
It's called a dumbwaiter.
- 这是用来做什么的？ - 这是专门送食物的
- Why is it called a waiter? - Because it carries food.
- 这会很吵吗？ - 这很安静…
- Why is it called dumb? - Because it doesn't speak.
而且也不会一直问些烦人的愚蠢问题
or ask countless idiotic questions.
你识字吗？
Can you read?
门上面写了「不准进入」
The door."No entry."
- 喔，这跟我有关系吗？ - 这是专门为你准备的
- What, does that mean me? - Especially you.
这里是房子的控制中心…
This is the control center from which I manage this entire household,
包括我的私人住所
as well as my personal quarters.
娜塔莉小姐可能会 允许你进入其他的房间…
Now, Miss Natalie may have granted you run of her home,
但是这里是我的私人禁区，明白吗？
but this is my domain and strictly off-limits. Understood?
还有什么问题？
Any more questions?
很好
Good.
嘿，茉莉，你在干什么？
Hey, Molly. Whatcha doing?
打扫房间
Cleanin' the house.
- 所有房间？ - 喔，不是，就只有这个房间
- Gross. - Oh, no, no. Not in this house.
来看，吸尘器打开
Watch. Vacuum, on.
- 吸尘器关闭 - 哇！这个壁炉可以自行清理
- Vacuum, off. - Wow! The place even cleans itself!
你还想看更酷的事情吗？
Want to see somethin' really cool?
芝麻开门
Open sesame.
哇！这里实在是太神奇了
Wow! This place is awesome.
是啊，没错！
Yes, it is.
要关掉音乐吗？
Music, off?
关闭音乐
Music, off.
我要去一下商店 一小时后就会回来
I'm off to the store. I'll be back in an hour or so,
对小孩子好一点
and don't pick on that dear child.
开门
Door, open.
她离开房子了
She's out of the house.
很好，障碍物已经没有了
All right. Coast is clear.
- 现在进去吧 - 等一下，你确定现在安全吗？
- Let's go. - Wait. Are you sure it's safe?
宝贝，假如不安全的话 我会带你进去吗？
Pumpkin, would I take you in there if it wasn't safe?
如果明天王子还是没来的话
It's just if the prince don't arrive till tomorrow,
我们还要继续待在这里吗？
why are we going in there now?
在采取行动之前 薇拉，你觉得…
To get the lay of the land. What do ya think, Vera?
我们明天进去就只是绑架小孩子？
We're just gonna go in there tomorrow and start grabbing kids?
「喔，大家都进这辆车」 不只是这样
"Ooh, everybody get in the van." No.
我们要想想绑架的适当地点、时间以及手段
We gotta figure out the where, the when, the how to get him out of there.
你知道成功犯罪的秘密吗？
Do you know the secret to criminal success?
就是不要被抓住
Not getting caught.
计划、准备，以及做好备案
Planning. Preparation. Preparedness.
「做好完全准备」 准备好做一个「有准备的人」
Be prepared. Be a prepared "preperator."
呃？这是我的座右铭 这也就是为什么我…
Eh? That's my motto, and that's why I'm…
- 是童子军的原因 - 不，是老大的原因！
- A boy scout. - No. The boss, eh?
- 谁是老大？ - 你是老大！
- Who's the boss? - You're the boss!
- 老大在哪里？ - 就在这里
Where's the boss? Right here.
- 嘿，老大，还有一位呢？ - 就是我啦
- Hey. Boss, party of one. - Right there!
好了，我们走，亲爱的
All right. Let's go, pookie.
不…不可能！
No. It can't be!
是他！是马文！
It is! It's Marv!
普雷斯特先生 普雷斯特先生，你在吗？
Mr. Prescott? Mr. Prescott, are you there?
普雷斯特先生！救命啊！
Mr. Prescott! Help!
马文，警报器是打开的
Marv, the alarm is on.
喔，不，我们现在该怎么办？
Oh, no. What are we gonna do?
看我的
Watch this, eh?
喔
Oh.
关闭警报器
Alarm, off.
- 嗯 - 开门
- Hmm. - Door, open.
- 啊 - 真是雕虫小技
- Ahh! - That is one handy gadget.
喔，你忘了 我的座右铭是什么？
Well, what's my motto?
你是老大？
You're the boss?
- 「做好完全准备」 - 对
- "Be prepared." Yeah. - Right.
我娶了一个「天才」！
I married a genius.
那是什么东西？是玩具吗？
What do you think that is? Is that a turkey ball?
放下来，好吗？
Look, just put that down, okay?
好了，你真像个惯窃
All right. Like a klepto here.
王子一定是待在某个房间
All right, the prince should be staying in one of these rooms.
- 我想那是一部电梯 - 不要
- I think that's an elevator. - Don't…
- 你不要让我头痛 - 你才让我头痛
- You give me such a headache. - You give me a headache.
- 是你让我头痛 - 是你让我头痛
- You're giving me a headache. - You give me a headache.
- 别推我 - 关门
- Don't push me. - Door, close.
- 你要让我发疯了 - 你才让我发疯
- You're driving me crazy. - You're driving me crazy.
- 你让我… - 喔，闭嘴
- You're driving me… - Oh, shut up.
开门
Door, open.
- 关门 - 我爱死了这东西
- Door, close. - I love this thing.
马文…
Marv.
门…怎么关上了
The door was… shutting.
这东西怎么了？开门
What's wrong with this thing? Door, open.
我想这里有人
I think there's somebody here.
有人在吗？
Anybody in here?
- 喔，不要乱叫，嘘！ - 你才嘘！
- Well, not now. Shh! - You shh!
- 你嘘！ - 你才嘘！
- You shh! Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh. - You shh! Shh!
可能王子早就来了
Maybe the prince came early.
什么…
What the…
是他，快过来
That's it. Come on.
哇！
Oh! Oh! Ow!
- 快走，宝贝 - 啊！马文！
- Come on, honey. - Uh! Marv!
喔！喔！喔！
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Oh! Ah!
啊， 啊， 啊， 啊， 啊！
Ay, ay, ay, ay, ah! Ow!
普雷斯特先生！ 普雷斯特先生！
Mr. Prescott! Mr. Prescott!
- 是你！ - 你好，马文
- You! - Hello, Marv.
喔
Well…
好久不见了
long time, no see.
- 对吧？小鬼 - 他是王子吗？
- Huh, kid? - Is that the prince?
不，他是凯文！凯文，薇拉 薇拉，凯文
No, that's Kevin. Kevin, Vera. Vera, Kevin.
如果他不是 我们马上离开这里吧
Well, if that ain't him, let's get outta here before somebody sees us.
我想我们该采取别的行动了
Yeah. I think we got the lay of the land.
我会回来的
I'll be back!
- 走吧！ - 好啦！
- Come on! - Oh, all right!
房子，自己清理
House, clean yourself up.
好，我应该试看看…
Well, it was worth a try.
我想，大家应该不会抓狂的
Okay, maybe they won't be too mad.
假如我告诉他们刚才发生的事
I mean, once I tell them what happened…
他们一定会谅解的
maybe they'll be okay with it.
- 看来是不会… - 这是…这是…
- Or maybe not. - What… what…
这是…
what…
- 这是… - 这是…
- What… - What…
好了，我知道这里看里来乱七八糟 但是…
Okay, I know it looks bad, but…
宝贝，这是…
Honey, what's the…
凯文，你…你… 你到底做了些什么？
Kevin, what… what… what have you done?
普雷斯特！ 普雷斯特！
Prescott! Prescott!
- 这个坏掉了！我刚才试过了 - 有什么事吗？夫人
- It's not working. I tried. - Yes, ma'am?
过来！马上过来！
Get up here! Now!
喔，刚才真的坏掉了
Well, it wasn't working.
凯文，到底是发生什么事了？
Kevin, what happened?
不是我，是那些窃贼用的
It wasn't me. It was the burglars.
- 窃贼？ - 是的，我还认识其中一人，他叫马文
- The burglars? - Yeah. And I recognized the one guy. Marv.
这件事…我有告诉过你吗？
Did I ever tell you about him? Well, that's another story.
就是他们想毁掉你们的房子
But the point is they were gonna rip off your house.
- 所以你就选择把它搞得一团乱 - 不，我只是想要保护这间房子
- So you chose instead to trash it? - No. I was trying to protect it.
- 搞得一团乱来保护它 - 为了…
- By trashing it? - What in the name of…
嘿，为什么我叫你的时候，你都不来？
Hey, why didn't you come when I was calling you?
普雷斯特…
Prescott,
你知道今天这里有窃贼入侵吗？
Were you aware of any burglars here today?
窃贼？
Burglars?
不知道，夫人 所有的警报都很正常
No, ma'am. All the alarms were on as usual.
或许是他们把它关掉的 我猜他们也有遥控器
Well, maybe they turned 'em off. They had one of these, you know.
对不起，夫人 我没有看见任何人进来，但是…
I saw no intruders, and except for… beg your pardon, ma'am…
我看到浴室的水龙头坏了 我一直都待在监视器前面
the briefest of bathroom breaks, my eyes were on the monitors at all times.
这小孩子怎么那么厉害 可以在短时间内把房子搞成这样…
How one child could do so much damage in the time it took me to…
- 喔，这超出我的理解范围了 - 真的不是我！
- well, it's quite beyond me. - It wasn't me!
喔，但这里没有其他人
Well, there was no one else here.
- 他在撒谎！ - 我没有
- He's lying! - Am not!
- 你在撒谎！ - 没有！
- Are too! - Am not!
- 你在撒谎 - 不管怎么说，先生…
- Are too! - With all due respect, sir,
我的确看见凯文在遥控那些设备…
I did see Master Kevin playing with the devices.
把整个房子当作一个大玩具
as if the house were a big toy.
这里唯一的小屁孩就是你的儿子
The only hooligan here today was your son.
等我一下
Give us a minute.
凯文
Kevin.
- 爸爸… - 凯文，坐下
- Kevin, sit. - Dad, I…
究竟是怎么一回事？
What's going on?
我跟你说了，是窃贼闯进了这间房子
I told you. The burglars broke into the house.
凯文，你知道我可以原谅你任何事情 但是除了撒谎
Kevin, you know I can forgive just about anything but lying.
喔，所以如果我把这里搞得一团乱 你也不会生气吗？可是我并没有做…
Oh, right. So you wouldn't get mad if I wrecked the place, which I didn't,
为什么硬要我承认… 那些我没做过的事
as long as I admit that I did, which I didn't?
喔，我想事情都过去了，啊…
Well, I thought this over and, uh…
我知道你很难控制
I understand that this is a difficult adjustment for you.
因为你平常就很过动
And it's only natural that you'd be acting out.
- 但是你得多注意一点 - 不，不是这样的
- It's a need for attention. - No, it isn't.
凯文！
Kevin!
不论如何…
Anyway…
不论如何 反正也没什么损失？
Anyway, what's a little damage?
还好有保险，不然就赔大了
It's not as if I'm not insured.
你还有什么要说的吗？
Well, do you have something to say?
谢谢你们
Thank you.
还有呢？
And?
我为这件事向你们道歉
I'm sorry for the damage of your house.
保全摄影机一定有录下了全部过程
Security cameras must have got the whole thing on tape.
什么？
What?
一定是普雷斯特关掉了摄影机
Prescott must have turned off the cameras.
真是不可思议
It's unbelievable.
真令人难以相信！
It is not to be believed!
我不敢相信这一切！
I can't believe this!
又是那个该死的小鬼
It's the lousy kid again.
每次都让我遇到他！
Everywhere I break into!
好像他老跟着我一样
It's like he's stalking me or something.
喔，马文 他只是一个小男孩
Come on, Marv. He's just a little boy.
喔，没错 但是那小鬼却给我大麻烦…
Yeah, well, I got big scars from that little…
不用担心
Never mind.
我告诉你一件事…
I'll tell you one thing,
这一次绝对不会让他再来破坏我们了
this time he's not gonna mess me up.
- 嗯 - 这次一定都能完美
- Mm-hmm. - This time it's all gonna go.
顺利进行的
smooth as silk.
因为这一次…
Because this time…
我有一个内应
I got an inside man.
喔
Oh.
嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
嘿！嘿，来吧，来吧
Hey! Hey, come on! Come on!
注意看路，安全第一！
Watch the road there! Safety first.
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
- 告诉我 - 我…啊…我…
- Tell me. - I, uh… I…
没干什么，我发誓
Nothing. I swear.
我觉得这些东西很好玩 所以就来瞧瞧
I just thought all of this was kinda cool, so I wanted to take a look at it.
你不能擅自进入别人的房间 也不能乱碰别人的东西
You don't go to other people's homes uninvited,
我没警告过你…
and you don't touch their things.
如果你再犯的话，我会怎样处置你吗？
Didn't I warn you what would happen if I ever caught you in here again?
并没有特别提到
Not specifically.
相信我
Trust me.
那一定不会很好过的
It won't be pleasant.
你有事吗？
What do you want?
我听见那个孩子叫了啊！
I thought I heard the boy. Ah!
我真的听到了
And indeed I did.
我不希望他再扰乱你的工作 所以我要把他带走
I don't want him bothering you anymore, so I'll just get him out of your way.
走吧，凯文
Come along, Kevin.
现在让我来照顾他
He'll be my responsibility from now on.
谢谢你救我，茉莉
Thank you for saving me, Molly.
普雷斯特是一个让人保持距离的好人
Prescott is a good person to stay away from.
他其实是其中一个坏蛋…
You're telling me. He's one of the bad guys…
那群坏蛋破门而入
The bad guys who broke into the house.
其实他们不算是破门而入 因为他们也有遥控器…
Although technically they didn't break in, because they had their own remote.
- 你觉得是谁给他们的？ - 普雷斯特？
- And who do you think gave them that? - Prescott?
- 嗯 - 真是令人难以置信！
- Mm-hmm. - That sounds a bit far-fetched to me.
我明白，你也许认为 我的想象力太过丰富
I know. And you probably think I have an overactive imagination.
大多数人都这么想 但是你一定要相信我
Most people do. But you have to believe me.
凯文，普雷斯特是一个孤独的人 他仅有的就是这份工作
Kevin, Prescott is a lonely man. The only thing he has is this job.
跟你说个小秘密 他讨厌在这里工作
And between you and me, he hates working here.
- 能做自己想做的事… - 这种感觉真的是太棒了
- But to do what you're suggesting… - Then it all makes perfect sense.
他讨厌这份工作 所以他才想要参与偷窃，然后离开这工作
He hates his job, so he tries to pull off a big heist so he can afford to quit.
- 啊，我不知道 - 听着
- Ah, I don't know. - Listen.
他总是说我在撒谎 其实我没有
He told my dad I was lying when I wasn't,
他把保全摄影机关了 这能证明一件事
and he shut off the security cameras, so it can only mean one thing.
- 证明什么 - 马文和他的新朋友…
- And that is? - Marv and his new friend…
有一个内应…
have an inside guy…
普雷斯特！
Prescott.
- 我想你是对的 - 我？
- I think you're right. - I am?
没错，你的想象力真的太过丰富
Yeah. You do have an overactive imagination.
但是我就是喜欢小孩子的这一点
But that's what I love about children.
我儿子也和你一样… 就如同你的年纪一样调皮
My own son was the same as you at your age… a real handful.
茉莉，你一定是个好母亲
You must have been a great mom, Molly.
你得控制好你的想象力，好吗？
Well, you just try to keep that imagination under control, okay?
你很清楚 今天发生了什么事
You were very understanding about what happened today.
凯文正在经历着一个艰困时刻
Well, Kevin's going through a difficult time.
当你父母离婚时 你一定会难过的
It's not easy when your parents split up.
相信我，我明白
Believe me, I know.
不过我们一定会度过的
But we'll get through it.
你会成为一个好继母的
You're gonna be a great stepmom.
我们应该想办法 让他觉得这里更像个家
I think we just need to figure out a way to make him feel more at home here.
也许做些圣诞节的活动会好一些
Maybe do some of the Christmas things he's used to doing,
比如布置圣诞树
like trimming the tree.
- 你自己布置吗？ - 当然，我自己布置
- You do that yourself? - Yes, I do that myself.
真有趣，这就是我们该做的事 我们来布置圣诞树
It's fun. That's exactly what we're gonna do. We're gonna trim the tree.
这样我们可以团结在一起 让我们更像一个家
It'll get us in the spirit of things, unite us as a family.
- 好吗？ - 好吧
- Okay. - Okay?
没有朋友，没有欢笑，没有白雪
No friends, no fun, no snow.
这次肯定会是一个 最糟糕的圣诞夜
This is definitely gonna be the worst Christmas ever.
嘿，凯文，你还好吗？
Hey, Kev. How you doing?
我们好像忘了今天应该做什么事？
What do you say we just forget about today and start over, huh?
- 你是指？ - 没错
- You mean it? - Yeah.
其实娜塔莉人很好
You know, Natalie's really a great person.
你应该多和她相处
You just gotta get to know her better.
我想我们应该让这个家充满欢乐气氛
I think we should start having a little more fun around here.
- 我可以一起参与 - 真的？
- I could live with that. - Yeah?
那我们马上来布置圣诞树吧？
Why don't we start by trimming that tree?
- 现在吗？ - 没错，马上行动吧！
- Now? - Sure. Why not?
喂
Hello.
我听不清楚 能把音乐关小声一点吗？
Hold on, I can't hear you. Can you turn down the music?
关掉音乐
Music, off.
你刚才说什么？
What did you say?
当然，我们待会就到 绝对不会耽误的
Well, of course we'll be there. We wouldn't miss it.
我等一下再给你回电话
Let me call you back.
玛格丽特正在市区报佳音 他
Evangelista's in town.
们打算待会约我们吃顿简单的晚餐…
Margaret's just throwing together a little impromptu supper,
我们可以去吗？
but we shouldn't go, should we?
好啊，不然你自己去，不用陪我们
Well, wh-why don't you just go ahead without me,
我和凯文要留在这里完成布置
and Kevin and I will finish up over here?
真的吗？你不介意吗？
Really? You wouldn't mind?
当然不会，毕竟他们也是你的朋友
No. They're your friends anyway.
你人真好 我不会太晚回家的
You're an angel. I won't be home late.
好吧
Okay.
我们布置到哪了？
Where were we?
- 你不需要因为我而留下来 - 不，我是真心想要留下来
- You don't have to stay because of me. - No, I want to stay.
嗯…
Really.
娜塔莉她每晚都出去吗？
So, does Natalie go out every night?
她很常出去，她总是充满了热情…
Pretty much. She leads a very exciting life…
甚至带给我前所未有的生活体验
more exciting than we're used to.
所以你不再感到枯燥乏味？
So you'd say you're not in a rut?
是的，我不再感到枯燥乏味 怎么了？
No, I'm not in a rut. Why?
我想这就是你离开的原因
I thought maybe that's why you left.
凯文，凯文，你知道吗…
Kevin. Kevin, you know…
我并不是为了和娜塔莉在一起 才离开你妈妈的
I didn't leave your mom to be with Natalie, okay?
虽然这种情况后来发生了
That just kind of happened later.
你想告诉我什么？
You wanna tell me about it?
大人的世界就是这么复杂
Adult relationships are just complicated.
有些人太早结婚 就像你妈妈和我一样…
Sometimes when two people get married really young like your mom and I did,
到最后会有一种感觉…
you just end up feeling kind of…
- 你好像错过了什么 - 没错
- You missed out on some things. - Yeah.
一个人外表长大成熟…
I mean, just 'cause you grow up on the outside,
不代表你的内心世界不能拥有欢乐
doesn't mean you wanna stop having fun, enjoying life.
爸爸，我知道有些人童心未泯
I know all about the inner child, Dad.
- 喔，真的吗？ - 这就是为什么有些大人喜欢开跑车
- Oh. You do, huh? - That's why old guys drive sports cars.
可能你是对的
You're probably right.
但是跑车的问题是…没有其他人的空间
But the trouble with sports cars… no room for anybody else.
也许最多能再多一个人的位置…
Maybe one other person, max.
但是如果你想体验一次真正的公路旅行…
But if you want to take a real road trip,
就得带着行李等等… 并没有办法留位置给朋友
with luggage and all, you don't even have room for a friend.
那些人也许过得很酷、很刺激…
I mean, they're cool and fast and all,
可是谁想要像他们一样 开着帅气的跑车，却是孤单一人呢？
but who wants to be in a nice car when you're all alone?
好了，看起来真是完美
Well, that looks just about perfect.
只剩下把星星挂上去了
All that's left to do now is put on the star.
凯文总是喜欢挂星星
Kevin always puts on the star.
没错，他喜欢，不是吗？
That's right. He does, doesn't he?
我总是举着他 然后给他开玩笑拉内裤
And I always hold him up, and then I give him a wedgie.
他在那边大惊小怪 我们都笑翻了
He makes a fuss. We all laugh.
我看我们今年得要用梯子了
Well, I guess we're just gonna have to use the ladder this year.
好了，爸爸 你可以把我放下来了
Okay, Dad, you can put me down now.
喔，看起来真漂亮
Wow. Looks pretty good.
我觉得看起来很棒
I think it looks great.
我想这是我们最棒的圣诞树了
I think it's our best tree yet.
嗨！
Hey!
- 圣诞快乐，妈妈 - 圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas, Mommy. - Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
喔！快看！
Oh! Look at that!
- 嘿嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. Hey. - Hey.
我把这个计算机芯片装在妈妈身上
I had this little computer chip installed in Mom,
我们正打算去找她来做早餐吃
and next Christmas, we're gonna get her to make some breakfast.
- 早安 - 早安
- Morning. - Mornin'.
早安，贪睡虫们 你们终于起床了
Good morning, sleepyheads. You're finally up.
你对我们的圣诞树做了什么啊？
What did you do to our tree?
喔，是我的错
Oh, that's my fault.
我每年都会叫人来布置圣诞树
I have a standing appointment with the tree decorators every year,
因为最近过得太开心了 所以我忘记取消了
and in all the excitement, I forgot to cancel.
你能原谅我吗？
Are you ever gonna forgive me?
你拆掉了我们的树吗？
You undid our tree?
反正它最后还是要被拆掉的啊
Well, it would have had to come down eventually anyway.
好了，凯文 来看看这些礼物，怎么样？
Yeah, come on, Kev. Look at all these presents, huh?
喔，来看，这有一件大礼物 我相信这件是属于…
Oh, wait. Ooh, here's a big one. I believe it has…
没错，上面有你的名字
yes, it has your name on it.
快来拆开它 这是我和娜塔莉送给你的
Come on. Why don't you open it up? It's from Natalie and me.
我不能明天圣诞节的时候再打开吗？
But shouldn't I open it tomorrow on Christmas?
你明天还有更多礼物呢 来吧，不要弄坏了
Ah, you got plenty to open tomorrow. Come on. One won't hurt.
继续
Go ahead.
超级间谍 窃听器和收听装置
Super spy bugging and listening device.
- 不酷吗？ - 很酷！谢谢你，爸爸！谢谢你，娜塔莉！
- Isn't that cool? - Yeah. Thanks, Dad. Thanks, Natalie.
我很高兴你有喜欢
I'm glad you like it.
- 嘿，妈妈，你要去哪？ - 我给凯文送点东西
- Hey, Mom, where you going? - I'm going to take Kevin some things.
妈妈，你要去哪？
Mom, where you going?
他没有干净的衣服…
He doesn't have any clean clothes with him,
我肯定他也没有玩具可玩
and I'm sure he doesn't have any toys to play with.
顺便去检查一下爸爸的女朋友，想去吗？
To check out Dad's girlfriend. Wanna go?
- 有什么需要帮忙的吗？ - 喔！
- May I help you? - Wow!
我来找凯文·麦卡斯特
I'm here for Kevin McCallister.
- 喔！ - 巴兹
- Wow! - Buzz.
- 你是来这里带他回家的吗？ - 不是，我有些东西要给他
- Are you here to take him home? - No, I have something for him.
请往这边走
Right this way.
你应该听的到这声音
You should be able to hear on that. Can you hear me?
- 我听起来怎么样啊 - 孩子们，跟近一点
- How do I sound? - Kids, stay close.
- 妈妈！ - 嘿！
- Mom! - Hey!
嘿！
Hey!
妈妈！啊！
Mmm! Ohh!
你们还记得娜塔莉吗？
Hey, you guys remember Natalie, right?
- 巴兹、梅根 - 嗨，娜塔莉
- Hi, Buzz, Megan. - Hi, Natalie.
喔，凯特，这是娜塔莉
Oh, and, uh, Kate, this is Natalie.
- 娜塔莉，这是凯特 - 你好，凯特
- Natalie, Kate. - Hello, Kate.
你好
Hello.
你们想要待一会吗？
So, are you guys gonna stay?
不，我只是给你送一些东西过来
No, no, I just brought you some of your stuff.
你们可以参观这房子
You guys gotta see this house.
- 可以吗？娜塔莉 - 当然，你们是我的客人
- Is that okay, Natalie? - Of course. Be my guest.
- 好美的树啊 - 它本来更好看
- Awesome tree! - It used to look better.
你头上戴的是什么啊？
Wait, what is this thing on your head?
是间谍工具，娜塔莉送给我的圣诞礼物
It's a spy kit that Natalie got me for an early Christmas present,
- 太酷了 - 真的吗？这真的很适合你
- And it's so cool. - Really? That was nice of you.
我很喜欢你的孩子
Well, I'm very fond of your kids.
我带你们见识一下 她送给我的飞机
I've gotta show you this airplane that she got me.
要喝杯咖啡吗？
Would you like a cup of coffee?
喔，不用了，谢谢
Oh, no, thank you.
我不知道
I, uh, didn't know he would have.
- 他有这么多的玩具 - 是吗？
- all this stuff to play with. - Yeah.
喔，天啊，给我看看
Oh, god. Hey. Let me… let me get that.
我不知道没有这个 他睡不睡得着
I wasn't even sure he could even sleep without it.
糟糕，你知道吗？
Gosh, you know what?
他竟然都没提起过这个
I cannot believe he hasn't even asked for it.
没关系 我们也能买其他的绒毛动物娃娃给他
Well, we could buy him another stuffed animal.
- 喔，不，不 - 不行
- Oh, no, no. - No.
- 就是这个，他的泰迪熊 - 不
- This is, uh… this is Teddy. - No.
泰迪熊一直是他的好朋友
Teddy is his transitional object.
是的
Yeah.
好朋友
Transitional object.
就像小孩子随身 携带的东西一样
It's like something very, very special a child carries with him everywhere.
你应该留一个备用
You're actually… you're supposed to have a spare,
以防万一
in case something happens to it.
- 当然，我们就只有这一个，还记得吗？ - 喔！我怎么会忘记呢？
- Of course, we only had one, remember? - Oh! How could I forget?
我们有一次在高速公路上开快车
We were driving down the highway,
那次真的有急事
like, really in a hurry, going somewhere.
凯文觉得
Of course, Kevin thinks,
泰迪熊需要一点新鲜空气
oh, possibly Teddy might want a little fresh air, right?
所以他把车窗摇下来 然后泰迪熊就飞出去了！
So he rolls down the window, and out flies Teddy!
他就突然失去理智！ 他一直哭，而且非常沮丧
He was ballistic. He was crying. He was so upset.
是…喔，我的…
It was… oh, my…
所以彼得把车停到路边 然后我下车找到小熊
So Peter pulls over, and I get out to retrieve the bear.
我到现在都不敢相信你竟然找到了
I still can't believe you did that.
还好是在慢车道 没有太多的车子
Well, it was the slow lane, and there wasn't much traffic.
如果没有了这只小熊 我真不知道他会怎么办？
Yeah, well, I don't know what he would have done if he had lost it.
我想凯文和王子在一起 一定会玩到很开心的…
Well, I think Kevin's gonna have so much fun playing with the prince…
他甚至不会去想念绒毛动物娃娃
that he's not even gonna miss the stuffed animal.
如果这房子里面全是孩子 这一定很美好
It's going to be so wonderful having a house full of children.
我非常期待有那么一天
I'm looking forward to it.
孩子们，小心花园的雕像
Children, watch the garden sculpture!
喔，我想我得快点离开…
Well, I… better get going.
不是我，是凯文
It wasn't me! It was Kevin!
不然他们可能会弄坏什么东西
Before they break something.
喔，我们马上要去机场接皇室成员
Well, we're off to the airport to pick up the royal family.
你们知道这是多么重要的事
You all know how important this is.
宴会服务人员马上就来了
Now, the caterers will be here momentarily.
而宾客们都会提前一个小时到达…
And the guests will arrive about an hour before.
让你们和皇室成员看到隆重盛大的场面
you and the royals make your grand entrance.
不用担心…
No need to worry, ma'am.
一切都能顺利进行的
Everything will be taken care of.
但愿一切都能事事顺利
It's just that I want everything to go right.
走吧，我们不能迟到
Come on. Let's not be late.
我不希望有出任何的差错 开门
I don't want one single thing to go wrong. Door, open.
绝对不能出差错
And nothing will.
喔，太好了！你们终于来了
Oh, good. You've finally arrived.
- 普雷斯特先生！普雷斯特先生！就是他们！ - 安静
- Mr. Prescott! Mr. Prescott! It's them! - Hush, you.
- 我马上带他离开 - 谢谢
- I'll get him out of your way. - Thank you.
他们就是那天的窃贼！ 就是他们啊！普雷斯特先生！
It's the burglars! It's the burglars! Aah! Mr. Prescott!
是马文！
It's Marv!
不过我猜你早就知道了
I guess you already knew that though.
你！仔细听着！ 我已经受够了你的闹剧
Listen, you. I have just about had enough of you and your melodrama!
今晚的宴会非常重要
Now, This is a very important night,
假如有必要的话，我会把你关起来…
and if I have to lock you up to keep you out of our way,
- 别以为我不敢！ - 看！
- don't think I won't do it. - Look!
喔！
Ow!
喔！喔！
Ow. Ow!
别烦我！你这个小鬼！
Don't trifle with me, you demon spawn!
藏在这个地方真是愚蠢
Now that's a foolish place to hide.
解决一个了，还有两个人
One down, two to go.
放我出去！放我出去！
Let me out of here! Let me out of here!
这里很冷！放我出去！
It's freezing cold back here! Let me out!
凯文，你有看见普雷斯特了吗？
Kevin, have you seen Prescott?
- 没有看到 - 啊，他每次都这样
- Not lately. - Ah, typical.
当你不需要他的时候，他总是在…
Always poking around when you don't want him,
而你需要他的时候…却找不到他
and when you need him, nowhere to be found.
啊！客人已经来了？
Ah! Guests already?
怎么没有礼貌性迟到呢？
Whatever happened to fashionably late?
喔，我不想自夸，但是…
Well, I don't like to boast, but…
没错，这是一场隆重盛大的宴会
Yes, it will be the party of the season.
喔，我要接另外一通电话 好的，再见
Oh, I'm getting another call. All right. See you there.
喂
Hello?
卡梅利娜，你好吗？
Carmelina, how are you?
什么？喔，不！
What? Oh, no!
他们被大雪困住了 航班也已经取消
They're snowed in. Their flight's been canceled.
喔，真令人沮丧
Well, so am I. Devastated.
喔，好吧，明天见
Well, all right. We'll see you tomorrow.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
我们现在该怎么办？ 今晚只能算是普通的宴会
What are we gonna do now? It's gonna be just an ordinary party.
与你一起度过的圣诞夜 对我而言绝不平凡
Christmas Eve at your place sounds anything but ordinary to me.
但这根本不能算是隆重盛大的宴会
It's hardly the party of the season.
彼得
Peter.
不如今晚来宣布我们的婚事，怎么样？
What if we announce our engagement tonight?
今晚？
Tonight?
我知道我们还要等到 你完成离婚手续…
I know we were gonna wait till after your divorce was final, but…
但是也只需要再几个星期了… 而且你的孩子也都知道了…
well, it's only a few weeks away and your kids already know,
这会让今晚的宴会与众不同
and it'll make tonight so special.
好，只要能让你高兴
Well, if it makes you happy.
耶！
Yes!
那些家伙跑到哪里了？
Where are those guys?
- 马文，我想要尿尿 - 薇拉，你下个星期再尿吧
- Marv, I gotta tinkle. - Vera, you can tinkle next week.
你可真会找时间！
Always in a hurry.
开门
Door, open.
好了，你还记得那个计划吗？
All right. Now, you remember the plan?
- 哪个计划？哈利的计划吗？ - 什么…不，不是哈利的计划！
- Which plan? Harry's plan? - What? No! Not Harry's plan!
- 就是那个使用绳子和袋子的计划！ - 你为什么要对我大吼大叫？
- The one involving rope and a bag! - Why are you yelling at me?
我没有大吼大叫…
I'm not yell…
- 你想起那个计划了吗？ - 想起来了
- Do you remember the plan? - Yeah.
- 现在，当王子上床去睡觉时… - 我们就把他绑进在袋子里
- Now, when the prince comes up to bed… - We bag him!
- 没错，我们要绑架那个小孩 - 你真是个天才，马文
- That's right. We kidnap the kid napping. - You're a genius, Marv.
没错，开门
That's right. Door, open.
当王子进了袋子
Now, the prince goes in the bag.
- 然后我们就把袋子扔出窗户 - 嗯
- The bag goes out the window. - Uh-huh.
接着，我们顺着绳子爬下去 关门
We climb down the rope. Door, close.
对
Right.
最后，大家都进到车子里去
Everybody in the van…
在别人发现之前，我们早就离开了
And we're gone before they know what hit 'em.
真是完美的计划，马文 既优雅又精简
Beautiful plan, Marv. Elegant in its simplicity.
好的，我们现在来试试看
Yeah. All right. Let's try it out.
你进去袋子里面
Get in the bag.
我？为什么不是你进去袋子？
Me? Why don't you get in the bag?
因为我是老大 进去袋子里，薇拉
Because I'm the boss. Get in the bag, Vera.
- 我不想进去袋子里面 - 薇拉，进去
- I don't wanna get in the bag. - Vera, just get in the bag! Please!
你没跟我说过要进去袋子里面
You didn't tell me I was gonna get in no bag.
我要制造一些神秘，这样才会有趣 喔，我在袋子里面了
I was saving it. It's gonna be fun. See, we're in the bag!
太好了，真棒
Nice. All right.
打开窗户
Window, open.
啊
Ahh.
马文，喔
Uh, Marv. Ooh. Oh.
亲爱的，不用担心，我有抓紧
Don't worry, honey. I got ya.
马文！让我慢慢地下去
Marv! Let me down easy.
宝贝，我会的
I always do, baby.
我不应该想的太轻而易举
Shouldn't have had that last piece of cake.
啊
Ahh…
好极了
Perfect.
开门
Door, open.
不用担心
Don't worry.
一切都在我掌握之中
Everything's under control.
喔，马文…
Uh, uh, Marv…
太简单了，但还是很酷
Easy, but still way cool.
谢谢你帮我垫背，宝贝
Thanks for breaking my fall, pumpkin.
我总是如此，宝贝，好了
I always do, baby. Okay.
给我离开这里！
Get out and stay out!
- 我知道你们想要干什么？ - 喔！聪明的小鬼，是什么啊？
- I know what you're trying to do. - Oh, yeah, wise guy? What?
你们想要绑架王子
You're trying to kidnap the prince.
闭嘴，你这个小白痴！
Shut up, ya little moron!
- 我要杀了他 - 好
- I'm gonna kill him. - Okay.
哦
Ooph!
薇拉，亲爱的，需要帮忙吗？
Vera, honey. Little help?
喔，宝贝！太好了，我非常需要
Oh, yeah, baby. That'd be great. I sure could use it.
我听得一清二楚
I got every word.
哦，不
Ow. No.
- 欢迎回来，怎么没看见皇室成员？ - 他们被大雪困住了
- Welcome back. Where's the royal family? - They were snowed in.
- 啊！ - 普雷斯特在哪里？
- Ah! - Where's Prescott?
- 我到处都找不到他 - 真是奇怪
- I can't find him anywhere. - That's odd.
没关系，茉莉 给每位宾客上香槟喝
Well, Molly, make sure everyone has champagne.
我们有一件重大的事情要宣布
We're going to make a special announcement.
好的，夫人
Yes, ma'am.
- 你好吗？ - 很高兴再见到你
- How are you? - Hi, how are you? Good to see you again.
各位来宾，大家能看我这边吗？
Everyone, may I have your attention?
哼？
Huh?
我要杀了他
I am gonna kill that…
啊！
Uuh!
今天是个很特别的夜晚 有件重大的事情要宣布
This is always a special night, and tonight may be even more special.
抓住他！
Get him!
凯文！
Kevin!
彼得和我要订婚了！
Peter and I are engaged!
普雷斯特？
Prescott?
我想情况不可能比现在更糟了
This could not be goin' worse.
马文，你很旺喔
Marv, you're on fire.
喔，谢谢你，宝贝 你自己也不差啊
Oh, thanks, baby. You're not so bad yourself.
不，亲爱的 是身上着火烧到旺了
No, sweetheart. You're really on fire.
好了，我正在想办法 你知道…啊！
Well, I try to work out. You know… aah!
啊！
Gaah! Aah!
- 哇！哇！哇！ - 凯文！
- Whoo! Whoo! Whoo! - Kevin!
我没有说谎 那些坏人又回来了
I'm not lying. The bad guys are back.
我们到处都没有找到
We're not getting anywhere.
凯文，我问了所有服务生和茉莉
Kevin, I spoke to all the caterers and to Molly.
除了你之外没有人看见
Nobody saw a thing but you.
这怎么可能？
Now, how could that be?
我不知道 但是我听到他们说要绑架王子
I don't know, but I heard they're gonna kidnap the prince.
- 你真的听到他们这么说 - 是的，我用窃听装置听到的
- You heard them say that? - Yeah, with my super spy bugging device.
而且普雷斯特也参与了这件事
And Prescott's involved with the whole thing.
这太荒谬了
This is absurd.
我要打电话确认一下
I'm going to call and make sure.
明天皇室成员的班机有没有问题？
the royal family's flight is okay for tomorrow.
凯文，我知道这是怎么一回事了！
Kevin, I know what's going on here.
- 真的吗？ - 是的
- You do? - Yeah.
你想破坏我和娜塔莉之间的关系
You're out to destroy my relationship with Natalie.
- 什么？ - 你知道今晚对她很重要
- What? - You knew how important.
所以你就来捣蛋
tonight was to her, and you went and pulled a crazy stunt like this.
- 不是这样的 - 我已经给了你很多机会
- That's not the truth. - I've given you a lot of leeway,
因为我知道你很难接受 我和你妈妈离婚的事
because I know how tough this divorce has been on you.
但是今晚，你实在是太过分了
But tonight you went way too far.
我要你回到自己的房间，好好的反省一下
I want you to go to your room and think about what you've done.
在你向娜塔莉道歉之后 我会找你谈谈
And when you're ready to apologize to Natalie, then we'll talk.
关门
Door, close.
乔治！你在这里啊，圣诞快乐！
Here you are, George! Merry Christmas!
- 喂？ - 是妈妈吗？
- Hello? - Mom?
凯文！
Kevin!
喔，凯文 我很高兴你打电话过来
Oh, Kevin. I'm so glad you called.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我很好，我正在看电影《风云人物》
Yeah, yeah. I'm just watching It's a Wonderful Life.
- 是吗？ - 你知道我多么喜欢这部电影
- You are? - You know how that gets to me.
- 在哪个频道？ - 第八频道
- What channel is it on? - Eight.
喔！
Ohh.
我就是喜欢这种完美结局的电影
I guess I'm just a sucker for happy endings.
今晚的宴会如何？ 你过得很开心吧？
So, how's your party? Are you havin' a good time?
没错，一切都很棒！ 那你呢？圣诞夜有开心吗？
Yeah, it's all right. How about you? Havin' a good Christmas Eve?
是的，很开心
Yeah. It's great.
- 我爱你！凯文 - 我也爱你，妈妈
- I love you, Kevin. - Love you too, Mom.
圣诞快乐！
Merry Christmas.
- 圣诞快乐 - 好了，再见
- Merry Christmas. - Okay. Bye.
- 凯文，你还没睡吗？ - 是
- Kevin, are you awake? - Yeah.
刚才的事，我们把你骂得很凶 你现在人没事吧？
Your father and I were a little rough on you before. Are you okay?
- 没事 - 很好
- Yeah. - Good.
因为如果你再犯错一次 你就会被赶出这栋房子
Because if you ever do anything like that again,
让你的人生晕头转向
you'll be out of this house so fast, your head will spin.
你的父母亲要离婚了
So your father's getting divorced. Boo-hoo.
但很多人的父母亲也都离婚了，这就是人生，你要去接受
Everyone's parents get divorced. That's life. You'll get over it.
但是你不能破坏我和你父亲的感情
But you're not gonna come between your father and me.
你父亲想把你留在身边 我也很赞成
He wants you in his life, and I think that's admirable.
如果你想跟他住在一起
But if you want him in your life…
你最好别找我麻烦
you better not cross me.
听清楚了吗？
Understood?
很好
Good.
我明天早上会叫人把窗户修好 祝你有个好梦
I'll have that window fixed first thing in the morning. Sweet dreams.
这是我们镇里最有钱的人 我的大哥乔治
To my big brother, George, the richest man in town.
我刚才和凯文好好的聊了一下
I've just had a nice little chat with Kevin.
我想我们开始认识对方了
I think we're beginning to understand each other better.
你在看什么？
What are you watching?
是电影《风云人物》 这要演一整晚
It's a Wonderful Life. They've been running it all night.
- 来和我一起看吧 - 我已经看过了
- Come on. Watch it with me. - I've seen it.
- 那又怎么样？ - 怎么样…
- So? - So…
我不明白怎么会有人反复地看同一部电影？
I don't understand people who watch movies over and over again.
我看过了，也哭过了 因此一次就够了
I saw it. I cried. Once was enough.
你是在开玩笑吧 凯特和我每年都和孩子们一起看的
You gotta be kidding. Kate and I watch this every year with the kids.
这是我们的家庭传统
It's a family tradition.
没关系
Well.
现在你将要拥有一个新的家庭
Now that you're going to have a new family,
或许需要新的传统
maybe it's time for some new traditions.
他们一定会回来的 如果没有人相信我的话…
They'll be back. And if no one believes me,
我就自己去抓他们
I'll have to catch 'em myself.
闭嘴，你这个小白痴！
Shut up, you little moron.
闭嘴，你这个白痴！
Shut up, you moron.
好，停止
Okay, stop.
转得更快
Spin faster.
到袋子里去 闭嘴，你这蠢蛋！
Get in the bag. Shut up, ya bag!
- 圣诞节的早晨到了 - 圣诞快乐，凯文
- Christmas morning. - Merry Christmas, Kevin.
- 圣诞快乐，爸爸 - 嘿！
- Merry Christmas, Dad! - Hey!
- 彼得，你准备好出发了吗 - 出发？
- Peter, are you ready to go? - Go?
你们要去哪里？
Go where?
凯文 娜塔莉和我要去接皇室成员
Kevin, Natalie and I gotta go pick up the royal family right now.
现在？但是我们还没有拆礼物啊？
Now? But aren't we gonna open presents?
等我们回来再拆
It's gonna have to wait till we get back.
但这是圣诞节 为什么一定要两个人去？
But it's Christmas. And why do you both have to go?
你知道，有些事情就算不想做也得去做
Look, you know how sometimes you gotta do things you don't wanna do?
而这件事就是其中之一
This is one of those times.
我们很快就会回来的，这样可以吗？
Hey, we'll be back before you know it, okay?
我相信在我们离开的这段时间 不会出任何的差错，对吧？
And I'm sure nothing will happen while we're gone. Am I right?
- 没错 - 很好
- Right. - Good.
待在这里，我们马上就回来
Hang in there. We won't be long.
开门
Door, open.
圣诞快乐，凯文
Merry Christmas, Kevin.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
喂？
Hello?
- 不，我们没睡 - 不是我！
- No, we're awake. - It wasn't me!
嘘！好，我们正要行动
Shh! All right. We're on our way.
这让我好紧张
Oy. Sure makes me nervous.
我们走，亲爱的
Let's go, pookie.
我就知道，他们来了
I knew it. Here they come.
首先要干掉内应…
First step, eliminate the inside man.
喔，普雷斯特先生？
Oh, Mr. Prescott?
普雷斯特先生，你在吗？
Mr. Prescott, are you in there?
- 在 - 普雷斯特先生…
- Yes. - Mr. Prescott,
- 你可以帮我的忙吗？ - 什么事？
- can you help me with something? - And what would that be?
- 又要喝奶昔，是吗？ - 不，我要一瓶酒
- Another milk shake, perhaps? - No. A bottle of wine.
- 什么？ - 娜塔莉说我们要去地下室拿酒
- Excuse me? - Natalie said we need to get.
因为今天皇室成员要来
some wine from the basement for the royal family.
希望你是说实话
If we must.
我想你是对的…
So I guess you're right.
今年的圣诞节不会下雪
We're not gonna have any snow this Christmas.
人的期望越少，就越不会出错
One can never go wrong with low expectations.
你知道吗？普雷斯特先生 和你相处的这几天
You know, Mr. Prescott, it's been great.
真的很愉快
spending time with you these last few days.
快乐的时间总是过得很快
Time flies when you're having fun.
我知道我们一开始相处得不好 但现在有变好了，而且越来越好
I know we got off to a bad start, but things can be better, much better.
因为你会困在下面，而我会留在上面
'Cause you're down there, and I'm up here.
过来吧
Come here.
小家伙，开门！让我出去！
Young man, open this door! Let me out of here!
- 喔！孩子！ - 喔！真开心见到你！
- Oh! - Oh, boy! Am I glad to see you!
那些绑匪要来了 但是这次我有先作准备
The kidnappers are coming, but this time I'm one step ahead of them.
我把他们的同伙锁在地下室了
And I locked their accomplice in the basement.
这是个完美的计划吧？
Is this a perfect plan, or what?
几乎完美，亲爱的，但是你弄错了一件事
It would be, dear, except for one thing…
普雷斯特并不是他们的同伙
Prescott is not their accomplice.
我才是
I am.
你…你是他们的内应？
You're… you're the inside man?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
嗨，妈妈
Hey, Mom.
我们来了
We're here.
喔，是的
Oh, yeah, yeah.
- 妈妈？他是你的儿子 - 我跟你说过，我儿子是个调皮的人
- "Mom"? He's your son? - I told you he was a handful.
- 现在，快点！ - 啊！放开我
- Aah! Hey! Get off of me! - Oh, now, come on!
这里有暗门或是其他东西吗？
Isn't there a trapdoor or something?
没有，对一个酒窖来说那没有必要
No. Not much demand for 'em in a wine cellar.
你说得对
Guess you're right.
你有什么办法吗？
Got any good ideas?
一个也没有
Not a one.
- 我有一部手机 - 太好了，我可以用吗？
- I do have a cell phone though. - Perfect! May I?
- 当然可以 - 谢谢
- Sure. - Thanks.
- 喂，是巴兹吗？ - 凯文，是你吗？
- Hello, Buzz? - Kevin, is that you?
- 没错，我是用手机打电话给你的 - 喔，是用手机
- Yeah. I'm calling from a cell phone. - Oh, a cell phone.
真是太棒了，讨厌鬼
Good for you, puke-face.
又是她给你的礼物吧？
Is that another present she gave you?
真会炫耀
What a showoff.
我再打一次
I'll try again.
巴兹，你先别挂电话 我跟你说
Buzz, before you hang up, I need to tell you something.
我要找妈妈讲电话
I need to talk to Mom.
好，你已经跟我说了
Okay. You told me.
我待会再打好了
I'll try again later.
你为什么会认为我是内应呢？
Why in heaven's name did you think I was the inside man?
因为你表现得古怪 所以我就以为你是…
Well, if you hadn't acted so strange, I wouldn't have thought you were…
内应
so strange.
这些人第一次进来的时候 你人在哪里？
And where were you the first time these guys broke in?
你为什么不回应对讲机？
Why didn't you answer the intercom?
你又为什么关掉摄影机？
Why did you shut off the cameras?
我并没有 但如果这些歹徒利用茉莉的遥控器…
I didn't. But if those thugs were using Molly's remote,
他们就可以关掉整个保全系统
they could've turned off the whole security system.
- 那你为什么认为我在说谎？ - 因为我认为只有你在那里
- But why'd you say I was lying? - Well, because I thought you were.
而且，我也不想让娜塔莉夫人知道…
And besides, I didn't want Miss Natalie to know that I'd been…
我在偷懒
well, napping on the job.
如果可以的话，那个女人会叫我 一天工作二十四个小时
That woman. If she could work me 24 hours a day, she would.
这实在是太不人道了 所以当她不在的时候，我…
It's downright inhuman, so whenever she's not here, I, uh…
- 你会偷偷的占便宜… - 我只是稍微休息一下
- You take advantage. - I take a break.
享受一下我应得的休闲时刻
A nice, well-deserved break.
所以我才没注意到 全部的摄影机和对讲机都被关掉了
With all the cameras and intercoms turned off, I didn't notice anything.
- 因此我… - 你掩盖了你的过失！
- So I… - You were covering your "whoo-hoo"!
的确是…
Precisely.
- 你还想打电话给你妈吗？ - 当然
- You want to try calling your mom again? - Sure.
- 喂？ - 妈妈？
- Hello? - Mom?
凯文！
Kevin!
等等，凯文，我听不到你的声音
Wait. Kevin, I can't hear you.
可能是因为我被锁在酒窖里了
That's probably 'cause I'm locked in a wine cellar.
不，亲爱的 我听不到你的声音，噪音太吵了
No, I… honey, I can't hear you. There's too much static.
我被锁在娜塔莉的酒窖里了！
I'm locked in Natalie's wine cellar!
- 你是打电话来说圣诞快乐吗？ - 妈妈，你有听到吗？
- Are you calling to say Merry Christmas? - Mom, are you there?
- 宝贝？ - 你有听到吗？妈妈？
- Sweetheart? - Are you there, Mom?
- 凯文？ - 妈妈？妈妈？
- Kevin? - Mom? Mom?
喔，真糟糕！
Oh, great!
没电了
The battery's dead.
嗯
Hmm.
这里是卡尔班的宅邸
Kalban residence.
嗨，我是凯特·麦卡斯特，凯文的妈妈 可以找一下凯文吗？
Hi, this is Kate McCallister, Kevin's mom. May I speak to him, please?
- 凯文现在人不在 - 这就奇怪了，他才刚打电话给我
- Kevin's not here right now. - That's strange. He just called.
真的吗？对了 他和他爸爸以及娜塔莉小姐出去了
Really? Well, he's out with his father and Miss Natalie.
喔，他一定是用他爸爸手机打的
Oh. Oh, he must have called from his dad's cell phone.
可能收讯不好，所以断线了
Well, that explains the line going dead.
好，谢谢你
Okay. Thank you.
这小鬼打电话给他妈妈
Little rascal called his mother.
- 需要我让他看看，谁才是老大？ - 坐下，马文
- You want me to go show him who's boss? - Sit down, Marv.
你不是老大，我才是老大
You're not the boss. I'm the boss.
好吧
Okay.
既然他的手机断线了 我不认为他还能给我们捣乱
His cell phone is dead. I don't think he'll be any more trouble.
算了
No.
还是吃饼干
Cookie.
喔！
Oh!
喂？
Hello?
彼得，是我，我打电话给凯文 我们刚刚断线了
Peter, it's me. I'm calling Kevin back. We got disconnected.
凯文？ 凯文没有和在我一起 他人在娜塔莉的房子里
Kevin? Kevin's not with me. He's… he's back at Natalie's house.
真的吗？ 有人跟我说你们在一起
Really? I was just told he's with you.
好了…好了 别担心，我相信一切都没事的
Well… well, don't worry, Kate. I mean, I'm sure everything's fine.
好吧
Okay.
喔，真是奇怪
Wow, that's weird.
- 有人告诉凯特说，凯文正和我们在一起 - 嗯
- Someone told Kate that Kevin's with us. - Hmm.
- 我们最好回去看看 - 不
- Maybe I better go back and check on him. - No.
他就是想要你这样 彼得，他在操纵你
That's exactly what he wants. Peter, he's manipulating you.
你没发觉每次都这样子？
Can't you see the pattern?
只要我们一出门，他就会扯后腿
Every time we leave the house, he pulls something.
他就是想吸引你的注意 并且破坏我们的感情
He's just trying to get your attention and sabotage me.
喂！有人在外面吗？喂！
Hello! Anybody out there? Hello!
我们必须想办法离开这里
There's gotta be something that we can do to get outta here.
有了
There is.
- 帮我搬这些箱子 - 好
- Help me move these boxes. - Okay.
那后面有什么呢？
But what's back there?
这是个好问题！
Definitely not a dumb question.
- 是食物升降机！ - 答对了
- The dumbwaiter! - Bingo.
- 希望它还能运作 - 对不起，普雷斯特先生，我误会你了
- Let's hope it still works. - I'm sorry I misjudged you, Mr. Prescott.
我也是
Likewise.
我还记得娜塔莉的表情…
I'll never forget Miss Natalie's reaction.
当她一回到家 看到你对她房子的所作所为
when she came home and saw what you'd done to the house.
我真的爱看她气急败坏的样子！
I do love watching her hyperventilate!
这就是这份工作中为数不多的乐趣
It's one of the few pleasures of this job.
如果你讨厌这工作 你为什么不辞职呢？
If you hate this job, why don't you quit?
工作可没那么好找
Jobs aren't that easy to come by.
就算找的到，新的工作说不定还更糟糕呢
Besides, I could end up working for someone far worse.
你不应该待在你讨厌的地方
You shouldn't stay someplace you hate just 'cause you're scared.
毕竟「人生苦短」
Life's too short.
嗯
Mmm.
在这里
And… voila.
看看你进不进的去
Let's see if you fit.
嗯，抱起来
Up.
小心头
Watch your head.
我一上去，就先放你出来
As soon as I get up, I'm gonna let you out.
你只要注意你自己就行，听到没？
You just take care of yourself, you hear?
我跟你说，我好像听到什么声音
I'm tellin' ya, I heard something.
没错，要保持警觉心，薇拉
All right. Stay very alert here, Vera.
既然我都这么说了 不如你下去检查一下酒窖？
I tell you what. Why don't you go down, check out the wine cellar?
- 好的 - 是，你去那里
- Okay. - Yeah. There you go.
我在下面！
Down here!
你最好待着…喔！
You better stay… oww!
薇拉！喔！啊！薇拉！
Vera! Ow! Aah! Vera!
- 怎么了？喔 - 按按钮！
- What? Ooh! - Hit the button!
- 坚持一下，宝贝 - 喔！不，不，按那个按钮！
- Hang on, baby! - Oh! No, no! Hit the button!
- 什么？我听不到你 - 按按钮！
- What? I can't hear you. - Hit the button!
- 喔！ - 喔！
- Oh! - Oww!
不，不！不是那个 是另一个按钮！
No, no! Not that one! The other button!
就是这个！啊！
That's it!
嘿！
Hey!
这个小鬼！
Man!
我在这里！
Over here!
嗨，妈妈
Hi, Mommy.
太好了！
Yes!
再见，开门！
See ya. Door, open!
娜塔莉，你去接皇室成员 我回去找凯文
Natalie, you go get the royals. I'm gonna go back and check on Kevin.
- 什么？现在吗？ - 没错，我感觉到一定是出事了
- What, now? - Yeah, somethin's up. I can sense it.
- 你应该要体谅为人父母的心情 - 话不能这么说
- Maybe you have to be a parent. - That's not fair.
你也知道我很关心小孩
You know how much I care about kids.
但是你有关心我的小孩吗？
How much do you care about my kid?
出租车！
Taxi!
凯文？你没事吧？
Kevin? Are you all right?
妈妈，你能开慢一点吗？ 凯文应该没事的
Mom, do you think you could slow down a little bit? Kevin's probably fine.
你只要注意看有没有警察？知道吗？
You just keep an eye out for cops, okay?
好吧，薇拉，你去检查客厅
All right, Vera. Go check out the living room.
看看他有没有躲在那里？
See if he's in there, all right?
天啊！我真敢不相信
God! I can't believe this.
我应该去上大学，
I shoulda gone to college.
只要两年！ 我就能成为一名牙体技术师，两年！
Two years, coulda been a dental technician. Two years!
马文！他在卧室！
Marv! He's in the bedroom!
- 妈妈？ - 去抓他！
- Mom? - Get him!
开门
Door, open.
发现了
Gotcha.
嗯，啊！
Uuh! Gaah!
啊！
Aah!
喔！
Ooh!
关门
Door, close.
- 嗨，茉莉！ - 进去那里面！
- Hey, Molly! - Get in there!
马文，亲爱的，你在里面吗？
Marv, honey. You in there?
闭嘴，薇拉
Shut up, Vera!
好，我只是想…
Well, okay. I was just tryin' to…
闭嘴，你这个白痴！
Shut up, you moron.
嘿，我不是白痴，你这个混蛋
Hey, I'm no moron, you jerk.
- 闭嘴，你这蠢蛋！ - 开门！
- Shut up, ya bag! - Door, open!
- 你在发什么神经？ - 你才发什么神经？
- What's wrong with you? - What's wrong with you?
我才不是蠢蛋，而且你知道吗？ 你也不是天才！
I'm no bag. And you know what? You ain't no genius!
- 薇拉，亲爱的… - 不，不要对我说「薇拉，亲爱的」！
- Vera, honey… - No! Don't "Vera, honey" me!
- 亲爱的… - 你根本没那个小鬼聪明，因为你完全…
You're not even as smart as this kid, who, in case you hadn't noticed,
被那个小鬼打败了！
is totally kickin' our butts!
好了，从现在开始 我是我自己的老大！
Well, from now on, I am my own boss!
- 薇拉，薇拉，亲爱的… - 不要叫我「亲爱的」！
- Vera. Vera, honey… - Don't "honey" me!
宝贝，宝贝
Pumpkin. Pumpkin.
马文！别理她！去抓那个小鬼 我几分钟后就出去
Marv! Forget about her! Get the kid! I'll be outta here in a few minutes.
喔！
Oh!
Whoa!
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
芝麻开门
Open sesame.
- 竟然有这玩意！ - 这太神奇了！
- Well, get a load of that. - Holy majolie!
来吧！薇拉！
Come on, Vera!
好了，快出来，小鬼！
All right! Come on out, kid!
啊！没关系
Ah! All right.
打开酒柜，打开书架
Open bar. Open bookshelf.
打开…书架 打开书…酒柜…架
Open… open book-bar. Open book-bar-shelf.
- 打开…开书…酒柜…鬼东西 - 芝麻开门
- Open… open book-bar-thing. - Open sesame.
真是愚蠢 哇！
That's stupid. Whoa!
现在谁是笨蛋？你这个笨蛋
Who's stupid now, stupid?
嗨，算了，离我远一点，行吗？
Hey, come on. Just get off me, all right?
我要提高注意力
I'm gonna take care of everything.
酒柜，芝麻回转
Bar, revolve sesame.
小心！我们会没事的
Watch this. It's all gonna be fine.
- 酒柜，停止 - 喔！越转越快了！
- Bar, stop. - Oh! It's goin' faster!
是，我知道，薇拉 我知道越转越快了！
Yeah, I know, Vera. I know it's goin' faster.
- 芝麻加速 - 老婆你人不舒服…
- Speed faster sesame. - Okay. The wife's not feelin'…
芝麻加速！
Faster sesame!
芝麻霹雳无敌快速
Maximum speed sesame.
芝麻停止
Stop sesame.
摔得不错喔，马文
Nice jump, Marv.
喔！
Ohh!
哇！
Oof!
大家圣诞快乐 这真是个美好的夜晚
Merry Christmas to all, and to all a good night.
晚安！ 啊！
Good night.
啊！
Aah!
- 普雷斯特先生 - 随时为你效劳
- Mr. Prescott! - At your service.
是你！真高兴见到你
Boy, am I glad to see you.
- 我想我们应该报警 - 好主意，普雷斯特先生
- Perhaps we should call the police. - Good idea, Mr. Prescott.
叫我普雷斯特就好
Just "Prescott" to you.
普雷斯特！
Prescott.
- 我记得你说过你不担心的 - 我有吗？
- I thought you said you weren't worried. - I don't know.
我感觉出事了
I just had a feeling.
凯文！
Kevin!
爸爸！
Dad!
- 妈妈！ - 妈妈？
- Mom! - Mom?
- 他们是谁？ - 啊哈！
- Who are they? - Uh-oh!
- 我们得快点离开！ - 快追上去！
- Let's get outta here! - Around the back!
- 我们也去追，快！ - 凯文！
- We're on it. Let's go! - Kevin!
喔喔！
Ooh-ooh!
是的！
Yes!
- 啊！ - 太好了！你们抓到了！
Yeah! Way to go, guys!
凯文！
Kevin!
- 凯文！ - 妈妈！
- Kevin! - Mom!
- 喔，亲爱的，很高兴你平安没事 - 啊！
- Oh, honey! I'm so glad you're all right. - Ohh!
- 我在这里 - 对不起，我没有相信你的话
- I am now! - I'm so sorry I didn't believe you.
嗯！嗯！
Mmm! Mmm!
警察已经来了
The police have been summoned.
我帮大家准备了许多有趣的行程
I've got lots of fun planned for your stay.
我们可以去瑞格利棒球场？还有水族馆？
Can we go to Wrigley Field? And the aquarium?
对了，你有小孩吗？
Do you have any kids?
没有 但我保证我们的行程
No. But I promise we'll have.
会非常刺激有趣！
a very exciting time.
真酷！
Cool!
喔，其实待在监狱也不算太差
Oh, come on. No, prison's not so bad.
- 喔，是吗？ - 是啊
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
- 每个星期四都有牛排吃 - 啊，我知道那间监狱
- On Thursdays you get Salisbury steak. - Yeah, I know about prison.
- 那就是我遇见你的地方 - 冷静，冷静
- That's where I met you. - Calm down. Calm down.
- 你要冷静下来 - 女士，嗯？
- You calm down. - Women, eh?
- 是的 - 嘿，别碰我
- Yeah. - Hey, don't touch me.
- 彼得！他干了什么好事？ - 非常棒，他拯救了一切，就是这样
- Peter! What's he done now? - Well, he saved the day, that's what.
你应该谢谢他
You should be thanking him.
茉莉 到底发生什么事了？
Molly? What in the world is going on?
他们想要绑架王子
It seems they were gonna kidnap the prince.
还好我们先逮捕他们，她是主谋
Best we can gather, she's the boss.
她是我的女佣，我是她的老板！
She's my maid. I'm her boss!
很好，看来你得找个新女佣了
Well, looks like you're gonna have to find a new maid.
恐怕还得找个新管家
And a new butler, I'm afraid.
- 我要辞职 - 辞职？
- I resign. - Resign?
但…为什么？
But… why?
因为有个聪明的小鬼说过「人生苦短」
Because as a wise young man once said, "Life's too short."
彼得，来帮我说说话
Peter, do something.
好，我来了
All right. Here goes.
娜塔莉
Natalie…
我想我错了…
I think I mistook.
因为爱而胡乱寻找刺激
infatuation and excitement for love.
听着，这… 这是你的世界，不是我的
Look, this-this… this is your world. It's not mine.
我现在要做的 就是陪伴我的家人
I mean, the whole time I was here, all I did was miss my family.
我们全家人沉浸在幸福之中
I'm in love with my wife and kids,
我是属于他们的
and I belong with them.
我要回家了
And I wanna come home.
我想你需要时间来理解这一切
I mean, I understand if you need time to think about it. I…
妈妈？
Mom?
喔！
Oh!
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
- I love you. - I love you.
小朋友，我们该如何 向你表达我们的祝贺之意？
Young man, how are we ever going to show you our gratitude?
你们全家一起来 跟我们过圣诞节，如何？
Would your family like to spend Christmas with our family?
听起来真棒
That sounds cool.
- 没事了吧？ - 没事了
- Is that okay? - Yes.
你确定要和他们在一起？
You're going to be with them?
今天？
Today?
在圣诞节？
On Christmas?
谢谢
Thank you.
放音乐
Music, on.
下雪
Snow, fall.
哈哈！嘿！
Ha ha! Hey!
我就知道今天是最棒的圣诞节！
I knew this was gonna be the best Christmas ever!